alrighty dude it's done amazing another
another episode in the bag that was such
a good interview yeah Cosmic is just
such such a smart dude such an amazing
person my alarm just went off outside
yeah man um yeah no I I think that was
one of the best episodes we've ever
reported to be honest that was pretty
sick yeah yeah that was amazing I mean
it there's so many hackers that we could
have talked to at this event and uh we
had we had picked just ahead of time
like let's let's talk to cosmen and then
yeah they're not winning the belt so we
nailed it yeah he he um he pulled off
the belt and and it was actually an
amazing performance as well so I don't
know that we get to talk too much about
it on on the Pod episode but yeah it
just multi-tenant uh multi-target life
hacking events is just a total skill of
itself and costumes the best at it yep
it's such a beast you have to be so
skilled and so flexible in your in your
skill set to be able to pull it off it's
just it's just amazing yeah absolutely
um all right well I mean I guess we
don't have too much to say before they
get into the episode but
um yeah if you guys would check out
um
criticalthinkingpodcast.io we have the
newsletter over there drop your email
and um let me see what is let me grab
cosman's Twitter really quickly I think
it's I want to say it's inhibitor 181 on
Twitter I believe it is yeah ctbb.show
for our newsletter and podcasts and
everything you can yeah about it all
there
um yeah and then uh in inhibitor 181 on
Twitter is cosmin legendary hacker
definitely give him a follow and yeah
enjoy the episode yeah
we've talked a lot about like going deep
right and like how if you pick any kind
of Target excuse me getting into it with
the application
right so like as you get more and more
realized into end up going deep which is
when you put it with getting I'm sorry
go ahead yeah well you're going deep
again
[Music]
[Applause]
anything
[Music]
dude here we are welcome to the Pod
thank you yeah I just wanna I just want
to say before we get started on this we
contacted cosmin before the event and we
said hey we're gonna we're gonna record
a session you want to join us and he
agreed and then he proceeded to win the
mvh for the live hacking event so
congratulations very good man
congratulations it was the most insane
timing because uh we were just we had
planned like days in advance that we
were going to take put you on the bottom
then uh we were just like we watched you
win and then we said to each other I
guess we picked a good guess
placed the right bets man so so this is
this is your this is your second MBH
right yeah hey amazing two NBA Squad it
is now it is now me you Franz and Josh
but as we discussed yesterday
um cosmin has a little bit of a unique
feature for his two mbhs you have
um two MB H's on life hacking events
with two Targets yes that's tricky man
yeah how does how does that work like I
feel like you have to split your time
between the two Targets because in order
to get selected for MBH in a two target
event you have to find great bugs on
both targets right yeah usually usually
is like that like doesn't mean that you
have to like look at all the Scopes of
each program and you have to pick a part
of the scope for each program you know
yeah and uh go deep try to find
something yeah it works out yeah so we
we won't say who it is or what it is but
there is a thing that you specialize in
that you are much better at than
everybody else and um at our at the
event that we just stay here here in
London there were two Targets and
somehow you managed to find your
specialty on both on both
you did a show and tell and in the first
show until you're like yeah so I was
clicking through and uh and I noticed
this checkbox and there's like two
options and one just says name of the
thing that you are specializing in and
some other thing and I was like of
course
dude that's that's really sick and I
think the advice that you that you gave
right there I mean that's definitely
applicable
um for winning multiple multiple uh
Target live hacking events you know
getting MBH for that but I think that's
really applicable to most life hacking
events as well is like a lot of the time
you you get these large companies that
say yeah just like hack Us in general
right and everyone's like holy crap I
gotta like run around and like try all
these different pieces of scope see
which one's vulnerable and then like but
no really I think my experience it's
been best to just pick one part of the
scope stick to it and just if you pick
the wrong thing like it's fine because
at the end of the day you're gonna be
less scattered than anyone else trying
to run around is that kind of what you
do yeah yeah for sure for sure just pick
something that you like and uh just grow
it in you can win you can lose you have
no idea because it could be like super
hard on the pretty shallow scope like
apparently large scope but shallow so
you don't have any idea about I don't
think for me personally it's not a good
idea I could focus uh on the whole scope
yeah because you don't have time to go
deep and you have a big chance of a Duke
oh yeah for this even I had just one
dupe one dude yeah so dang that's pretty
sick man yeah very awesome yeah so it's
really interesting because I was
thinking like
we've talked a lot about like going deep
right and like how if you pick any kind
of Target excuse me Joe getting inside
it with the athletes
right so like as you get more and more
realized into end up going deep with
this when you put it with getting I'm
sorry go ahead yeah well you're going
deep and getting it yeah don't even
getting into it man okay lovely yeah um
but like you can kind of apply that to
any any type of work like if you just
like focus in and you learn intimately
like how stuff is working like what are
the different pieces what are the
different aspects of this application
how do they communicate together you can
build out that solid understanding and
find the really really deep bugs but
you've managed to do this with this
technology that is so widely used that
it's like it's almost
program and Target agnostic right so so
you can just be like this target uses
technology yeah I know technology yeah
let's go right yes right it's almost
like learning like SQL injection it's
almost like a generic kind of knowledge
at this point yeah because it's so
widely used and you're so familiar with
it like I would reckon you're probably
more knowledgeable than employees
I'm sure they've tried I mean well okay
we won't we won't go to that path but
I'd imagine you've gotten some some job
you know offers from X X company that
we're that we're talking about but um
yeah no and I think but going back to
live hacking event strategy I think when
you do pick a specific like part of the
application it's really easy to think
like oh man like I've picked the wrong
part of the application I mean I had
that same mentality during this event
like oh shoot like I definitely
especially when you see the report
counts go up for other people and you're
and you've maybe just got like a couple
of highs or something like that it's
really hard to think about that so how
do you deal with the with the mental
piece of it and do you struggle it with
like uh man
um you know imposter syndrome and I'm
not finding the volumes in the right
part of the application yeah yeah so for
sure this uh this happens this happens
yeah
um but uh I I usually persist yeah I
just push through it yeah just push
through it like to go through it and it
usually actually pays off absolutely
yeah because uh there's like sometimes
the it's really hard to set up the all
the tools oh my gosh and it's a pain and
after you do it it's like a new venue is
open for you to find like yeah very
stuff and you can really change really
fast you can go really down but then
it's a huge up yeah
um
no go ahead go ahead and mute it before
it gets uh gets too BP
yeah no no that that makes sense man and
I think it is it's it that's a big part
of book Downey I think that's
underestimated is that sort of mental
toughness that's required to kind of
push through you know and and I you you
see this and I'm sure you you all get
the DMS as well but I get a bunch of DMS
every week from from do you have your
DMs open on Twitter or no no I have them
I have them open yeah so like like
so many DMS from people being like how
do I find these bugs and I'm like well
you sit down and then you try to hack it
and then you fail and then you try to
hack it and then you fail and then you
try to hack it and you fail and you
complete you do that like 20 times until
you actually find a bug after anywhere
from three to Thirty Days exactly it'll
click yeah exactly yeah so I actually
wanted to like
since you've been hacking on the same
like the same type of technology for
like so so long
um I have a couple questions one is
there stuff that like still surprises
you like new stuff that you learn as
you're hacking that you didn't know
before or is it pretty much like very
predictable at this point yeah so it
depends like some packs are really
predictable like you know what's going
on you can imagine what they use how to
use you know it should not be vulnerable
and so you can just like look a bit try
to understand it like on the big picture
but also new parts are added like you
have maybe like a new API you have
something you expose I'm sure that's
exciting yeah yeah and uh like it adds
to the pieces of the puzzle for the for
the whole image so I think it's it's a
it's a little bit of both sometimes it's
tedious sometimes it's exciting but you
can't have everything do you have to
stretch yourself to look for new
Innovative Vons in that rather than just
going back to your you know bread and
butter your your default for that for
that for this target or you know is that
something that comes pretty naturally uh
so I think I do it consciously so
sometimes I go back to them but in Botox
sometimes I try to like to go deep in a
very specific piece of that and do
something which sometimes I spend like
weeks yeah just trying to understand
something trying to go deeper and look
in it and then
um I can apply it to like a really big
scope so you have to like I personally
consciously choose what to do because I
also try to imagine how would that be
applicable to the big picture so do you
do you like intentionally have like
because once once you've been working on
one target for so long I feel like in
the beginning when you're introduced to
a Target you're just trying to like get
in the zone you're trying to get the
feel for the application the lay of the
land but then once you've been on a
target for so long do you have to have
like planning meetings with yourself and
be like all right in in one week I'm
gonna like check in and be like all
right do I need to Pivot or do I need to
stay or like set goals or is it mostly
just sort of on the fly like okay I'm
kind of spinning my wheels here I'm not
getting anywhere
um you know I'm sure maybe I should
pivot how does that work for you yeah so
uh for sure I don't do any plans
I'm not a psychopath so so my notes are
in text files so are they really yeah
it's nothing special that's another big
topic we've talked about is notes but
we'll come back yeah yeah so uh
definitely I think it's uh how feel like
on the mental level like if I try to do
something doesn't work doesn't doesn't
work I I just try to change it and do
the other thing yeah you know so but
then okay but and this is another common
question that I get all the time where
do you draw the line for that like how
do you know do you do you have any
methodology or is it just gut to when to
draw the line and I was trying to
quantify it the other day because I we
get this question a lot like where do
you where do you decide okay this is the
work I need to move on versus
persisting and I think for me it's like
probably five or six mental iterations
of I actually can't find anything else
here or like I'm something I feel like
I've hit a wall and then I try to push
through like maybe five times before I
thought okay actually I need to move on
well and I think like that that point
you made like mental iterations yeah
really important right it's not like
it's not like attempts right because I
was talking with some other hackers at
this event yeah specifically about race
conditions yeah and oh my God and like
there was one risk condition that
somebody found where they were like yeah
it was like one in 25 that it hit okay
okay but that guy's kind of nuts yes but
but like he's kind of crazy he's like a
little bit crazy like so maybe that's
what you need a little bit of crazy yeah
like there's just I think with some bugs
there's just like you have a gut
instinct and you can't explain why yeah
but you can just feel it yeah it works
right yeah yeah yeah
so I mean what do you think for you like
mental iterations wise or how do you
tell when to give up on a certain path
or continue down uh yeah I think it's a
God thing also I don't think I do that
many iterations but I usually come back
to the same logic oh really
yeah so like actually in uh one of the
bugs I presented yeah yeah I did some
Integrations it did not work then I went
uh the second one or the first one for
us uh because
mph and over to show like two show and
tells and I'm just like on both nights
which I think probably won't want him in
the NBA yeah it's kind of crazy as a
basically to answer this outfit did not
work then I went outside to go walk
without thinking I'm sorry was it show
and tell one or two one okay yeah yeah I
thought yeah okay I will try that and it
worked like I was actually thinking
about it so wait okay so so yeah walk me
through your thoughts do you try to
approach it as like an employee or how
are you thinking about it when you're
when you're churning in your head about
those iterations and what things you if
it's not working what you want to try
next is are you trying to think like how
is this written or is it more like what
things have I seen before that it might
be vulnerable to or like how are you
thinking about that yeah so this book
this particular case of talking to right
yeah yeah so I'm pretty
what was going on in the background so
it was pretty cool yeah what was going
on because I could confirm it to like
from various tests right I've seen like
the short version of that yeah
um
and I just uh first I thought what could
I do there what can I do there so I just
went a bit of the documentation yeah I I
left and then uh
freaking dogs yeah and uh it just hit me
like I don't know subconsciously yeah
it's a couple couple comments on this
one he said you said you went outside
and you did some work right that that is
big that is that is really big like you
can definitely that is definitely
something that gets the juices flowing
and gets creativity rolling I don't know
about you but like the best place for me
to think is on the toilet like a shower
toilet hot tub shower thoughts
showers good right yeah I I tell you man
you guys gotta invest in the hot tub
like yeah I always whenever I'm I'm I
mean I seriously mean it it is an
investment man I have made money off of
it it's like an elevated shower because
when you get in the hot tub and you just
start like levitating like and then you
just like Ascend to higher levels of bug
Bounty I think
um no but but that's really good and and
I think when it comes to gut related
stuff right you that that
we we try to quantify it just to be
clear for all of you that are listening
being like don't tell me it's gut like
this also comes with experience for sure
right that's exactly what I was gonna
say right you have to put in the Reps to
get the gut right right it's like that
combination of of you have to be like
consuming knowledge and stuff because if
you if you just learn like imagine
you're in school right you learn
everything up to like the 12th grade and
then you never learn anything again
you're never going to like go beyond
that right because yeah you just you
have to keep consuming and learning new
things if you want to progress and so
that applies to like bug bounty in the
same way where like if there's a
technology or anything that you're
hacking like if you just stop like
that's as limited as you're gonna be
you're if you don't learn new techniques
if you don't learn about how
Technology's work then that's it that's
where you're going to end and like that
might be good for you but like
yeah this is how you get two fehs yeah
yeah exactly and on one hand I think I
think the gut answer might be annoying
for most people but I feel like that's
how most people do most successful
hackers do respond it's like I just
somehow felt it that it was there you
know but on the other hand I feel like
that should be reassuring as well
because at the end of the day there's no
like crazy methodology you've got to
train yourself to stick to it's just
you've got to just do it a lot right so
right I mean do you agree yeah
if I think in this moment with the
current knowledge I have I missed dozens
of dozens of bugs in the beginning oh
yeah
yeah gut experience and stuff like that
yeah absolutely so you mentioned that
you use text files for for notes
um I recently started using notion
actually oh my God for notes just
because like you could you could have
sub pages and stuff we've talked about
how Joel is a freak about organization
like okay so recently I was I like I
just I just felt like a great system for
me because I can have like one large
thing that's like hacker one or whatever
and then underneath that I can create
one for like whatever program I'm
hacking on and then I can just do
bullets and unstructured stuff and I
could just toss like brain dumps in
there little Snippets and stuff right so
it are is it literally just like txt
files for you okay yeah
so when you say takes the files you make
it sound elevators
there's no extension
yeah
okay so uh
seven text wires oh okay
literally notes the other one is Greeks
the other one is mobile nice and that
doesn't have my uh program name yeah
that's
yeah Yeah because sometimes I don't know
in which one is
I have to grab it
yeah for yeah man I mean it just makes
me feel better about like you know when
you hear stuff like this or you hear
Eric talk about like I think he's been
pretty public about this but like he
uses VBA you know and Eric being uh
today's Nano just you know the the whole
is one of the most you know amazing
automation hackers out there but is his
system and he'll acknowledges just
totally like taped together with like
you know SGP and like and then God's
been you know the the The Legend of a
one program Master takes notes in like
one one file called notes and one file
called tricks
if you want I want to hear something
really funny yeah
how I name my book
I don't have a name it's like
[Laughter]
okay
I can't do ASDF anymore oh my gosh dude
that is that's Psychopathic Behavior
right there that is definitely if I have
something really interesting and I have
to start the new project like for this
event I started like five five projects
well yeah without targets I I literally
learned the name on the project is
interesting so I know in the drop down
okay so I definitely don't do that with
the profiles like I I intentionally name
all my verb files so I know where my
requests are husband but like I
definitely do that same thing when I'm
like creating multiple objects in a in a
you know at an actual software that I'm
trying to hack like I'll name like like
for example um you know there's like
various documents in one of the targets
we're working on and every time I was
like you know ASDF and then it like has
the same one and then I'll forget which
like one I'm trying to attack in a
specific scenario so then I'll just
rename one of them this one and then
I'll do that like three times so there's
like four named this one and then it's
like no really this one you know like I
used to do that with all my payloads
and then eventually I was like I can't I
can't I need to like start naming these
like real names because I'll come back
to a program after like a year and I'll
I'll see all my old files and I'm like I
have no idea what these are yeah like I
I was I was going back to a program
yesterday and I had uh I had one file
called this [__] is really interesting
dot burp
I was like oh my God what is that I
don't even know great job self you click
baited me all right I'll check it out
nah it's funny though because you know
and I I was working with with Sean
um e-s-s-y
um
w-h-y-e-s-why during this event a little
bit and uh he just he just names
everything [__] it like like literally
and I'm just like Shawn are you gonna
like uh put that in your POC and he's
like [__] it like I'm just like okay all
right like that seems a little bit off
but you know hey if it works for you it
works oh my gosh so amazing yeah this
doesn't does not mean it's the good way
right right yeah that's what works right
for you at least yeah just yeah I mean
that's a great point though because like
even though we even though we're all you
know towards the towards the top Echelon
um for pug Bounty stuff it doesn't mean
that there's not a lot of improvements
that could be made so you know there's
there's definitely someone up here in in
the top Echelon as well that maybe
misses some of our gut related stuff but
also is like organized as Frick like um
I I well yeah I'll shout out mayonnaise
right I've talked to this guy um you
know he's another guy that's just a
legend the yearly number one in the US
yeah yeah just don't run anymore I'm
coming foreign yeah
um but he uh he he's extremely organized
you know and he has a whole system for
organizing data and he never lets
anything fall through the cracks and
that's just his thing and it really
helps him
um and so yeah there it takes all time
all types I think and that's one of the
Great Value ad props for bug Bounty is
that we
all different eyes are needed to secure
an attack surface and you need some of
the you know sort of chaotic more just
disorganized eyes you need the hyper
focused eyes you need the absolute
lunatics that only do Unicode
normalization bugs Andre
[Laughter]
yeah and just all people that only do
cosmic bugs you know
um and so yeah it definitely it
definitely takes all types yeah so when
when you're like
at as you continue to hack on your main
target
um do you have any type of like
monitoring or automation like how do you
know when they come out with new
features do you just kind of have your
finger on the pulse all the time or how
do you how do you stay up to date and
make sure that you're not falling behind
with with the new features and stuff
that they're adding uh yeah so I don't
have any like monitoring tooling uh the
tools I have okay just like basic
con and
they can do Deltas so like I know what's
new but I have to run it like manually I
have like also a big custom automation
tool but it doesn't help me figure out
what's new that's all but I'm basically
subscribe to the newsletterx places I
follow them on Twitter not actually that
actually got me like three or four bugs
wow just like seeing some tweets well we
got this we got that we got that so
that's almost like some OS int level
stuff you know like you're you're you're
you're you're watching you know you're
subscribing to their changelog their
newsletter their their Twitter feed and
then when you see features come up you
know you have that product level
expertise to know oh wait that's
actually sounds really interesting and
then you dive into that yeah yeah and
they also have like a big releases with
the documentation
released so uh I look so I look through
those I'm a little behind now yeah
actually like but uh well yeah you said
you said lately you you don't actually
have a ton of or at least for this event
the 31 you didn't actually have a bunch
of time to hack right yeah I mean I had
like three or four full days and then uh
and what I also did like
like five hours in the evenings yeah
four to five hours yeah and you told me
before this pod that you you only really
sleep like five or six hours a night is
that right
it was around six hours six hours does
it for you yeah six songs definitely
does it
um do you do
okay so there's a clarification there
though like do you wake up after six
hours and feel rested or do you wake up
after six hours and be like okay I could
do my life yeah he's like what is
wrestling have a baby basically yeah
yeah exactly
the baby yeah but like uh I went to
sleep Back At One and walk alone at six
and have addressed it's like oh wow like
my my alarm was like at seven so
whatever yeah I mean do you feel like
you need a full am I the only one that
needs like actually eight hours of sleep
it's really weird actually like this
trip I've been getting like way less the
sleep that I normally do and I've been
feeling more alert than I normally do
and I'm not sure if it's just because
it's like jet lag or what but
um yeah I do wonder is that I I woke him
up like 30 minutes before I reported
this podcast by knocking on his door and
calling him like six times yes I like I
was having a nice dream and then I just
here
get up uh and then I was like oh [__]
I don't know
no yeah I I think I think um yeah I
don't know for me I have to have at
least seven hours of sleep if it's six
like I can do that for a couple days but
after that it starts you know sort of
compounding
um and my brain definitely doesn't work
quite as well and I have to give it to
props all the European hackers because
like yeah you guys come to the US all
the freaking time and jet lag and it's
it's pretty bad yeah we wake up at like
two and what I slept for hours it's
doing not sleeping it sucks yeah but
yeah do you ever hack like do you have
to ever have to like wake up in the
middle of the night to hear the baby and
you just like get an idea and go hack
something or no
I would regret it and I I actually could
like two people that don't have a baby
yeah there's hacking in
education was like like a super
exception for me because I
I cannot almost like never hack in the
evening yeah so you you you
um you're full-time as well right yeah
yeah so we're two full-time Hunters here
and I think
for me one of the things that I've
noticed and maybe you can comment on
this as well is that I struggle with
finding a sense of normal
in the midst of the life hacking events
right because like I feel like I sort of
live my life from Life hacking event to
life hacking event like I'm I'm so
dislike hacking and it's over I'm gonna
take a couple uh you know a week or two
to like chill and then either I'm
prepping for the next life hacking event
oh and that's another intense period of
like you know yeah I don't know maybe 10
hour days you know sometimes more but
you know but sometimes not and and in
the meantime like I've got enough
bandwidth to like do a couple things on
the side
um but like most of the time and my
normal gets disrupted every you know
every month or two because I'm doing
this big travel and and before that big
travel I'm intensely focused on a Target
so I mean do you feel that as well do
you feel like you have a sense of
normalcy in your life uh it's it's it's
it's hugged it's hugged I mean like uh
yeah exactly like you like you said I
also think you usually take time off for
a week or something whatever just also
spend more time with the baby because I
miss him though yeah
all of those and then I'm yeah basically
you have to put up for the next event
but in between I have to do some other
stuff get that done then cover the event
Focus that gets in the way of maybe
other stuff and yeah just fly and then
go back and yeah it's it's pretty hard I
thought they just have if I'm in between
just have some normal hacking out in the
morning and until like 3:30 or something
I should go three with a big like lunch
meeting break
so you said you know normally you're you
know you're doing from from you know
you've got the live hacking events but
in your normal thing you're you're
hacking in the morning and then you're
you're cutting out at around three or
three Thirty yeah and in between
lunch break yeah yeah it's nice man I I
love being a full-time book Bounty
Hunter because at the end of the day you
can set your own schedule pretty freely
and you know if you do want to go and
take a vacation or you know get a you
know a long lunch with your wife or
something like that does your wife work
from home or does she go into an office
or what oh she's a magic so she's in the
hospital oh lovely or goes to the
hospital wow that's that's a lot then
this is uh she's still on the
but your kid's like a year and a half
yeah Germany's what the heck dude
Germany is nice in the USA like four
years the US is like I'll give you three
days
I'm gonna need a doctor's note for more
than three days like she was different
yeah I'm sure it is wow that's that is
really awesome though but I guess you
know on the flip side of that you're
paying a lot of taxes on all these
values huh yeah yeah for sure for sure
it's uh I think I'm basically scratch
off like 45 percent
dude
that hurts that hurts yeah
but yeah no it's good to have that that
work-life balance and that um and I
think that is a struggle for all full
full actually you've done full time for
for longer than me now four years four
years dude nice I'm at I'm at just I'm
at just over three now three and a half
yeah and so I don't actually remember
like 100 yeah but I I think that sounds
about right around four years wow when
you first started hacking
what Drew you to your specialty like
what what Drew you towards like hacking
on that was that something that you were
you had already used at work were you
familiar with or something or like what
what like Drew you to focus on that it
was pure luck okay
straight here on critical thinking like
yeah yeah
pretty soon uh
it is a private program so I really
invited there uh my knowledge was like
really low but I found some stuff so it
kind of went like UPS Downs up downs but
the trend was like going up that that's
really interesting because I feel like
with some with a new program sometimes
you'll you'll you'll get that Trend and
then it'll kind of drop back down a
little bit too you know so if you see a
very consistent like upward Trend yeah
it might be a good a good time to say
like okay well this might be my program
yeah for sure for sure and I I didn't
like do some that huge planning right in
my mind because I knew we could do it
for years right right uh but also
tweeted me very well
um so I just like stick there and then
when I realized it's full potential I
went to like yeah
I don't know if you can comment on this
but like what is the
what is the I feel like this program
that you hack on has a longer turnaround
time than some of the other programs do
you how do you deal with that and yeah
uh so I think yeah if you do full-time
bug Bounty yeah I think it's super
important to always be stable like from
a financial point of view like you you
should not do it if you're like stressed
out like Bountiful stress it's it's a
no-go it's terrible yeah it's terrible
yeah uh so basically I just submit to
bug and then I forget about it it's just
like that
um yeah it can be paid in like a few
weeks can be paid a few months even more
but it doesn't really matter to you at
that point yeah exactly it doesn't
matter like I think my update requesting
is every like three to four months oh
really yeah wow geez that's that's
pretty intense and I think Alex Chapman
Alex Chapman other hacker that's that's
full time and uh and I think he sort of
coined the term or at least he was the
first one that I heard talk about like a
vulnerability pipeline being important
as a full-time hacker because you are a
full-time Bounty Hunter because you you
know you're not always going to be able
to get a quick turnaround on the
programs that are going to give you the
best value for your time yes and so uh
you know you you submit the bug and you
kind of forget about it or you have
patience and you know you're getting
paid today for the bugs you found weeks
ago and just like husband said if you're
if you're doing bug down in a way that's
stressed out or you're financially tight
then you're you're going to be needing
that payment faster and it's going to
make you stressed and it's going to be
less able to focus on the program and
focus on just sort of Chilly hacking and
so I think I think you know I I've known
this for a little while you know this
thing about not being able to do
full-time bookbonnie stressed out but um
I think it's concrete today in my mind
now where it's like if somebody message
me and says hey you know do you think I
could do bug bounty and make just a
couple Grand because I really need a
couple Grand because you know XYZ I'm
just gonna say literally no it's not an
option no you know just don't do it like
go find something that it's gonna give
you money for time not money for results
right right yeah exactly yeah yeah
because we're against the odds we've
talked about this so many times like bug
Bounty is literally going against the
odds you're you're going against like
security teams it's like yeah can I find
the things that they missed can I find
the things that they did wrong yeah and
you don't then that's like kind of a
good thing but also like you know you
can't really follow yourself it's not
it's not entirely skill based yeah some
of it that is completely out of your
control like there just might not be
alone there and yeah you might have just
been looking at something for a day and
not found anything there yeah it's not
there a little a little double click
into the live hacking event scene you
know we have these channels these slack
channels that we use for the live
hacking events and one of the most
popular channels is the meme Channel
yeah and and and like the memes at these
events are legendary like every every
time we have my wife and I have a habit
after the event's over we just like go
back to the to the you know room sit in
the bed and go through all the memes
from the from the live hacking event and
and we'll laugh about them
um one of the ones we saw last night was
just this like you know a meme
describing the fact that like oh well
you know there's a bunch of people that
are way smarter than me trying to
prevent me from hacking this target all
the time you know and and I forget what
the format of the meme was but it you
know it kind of hit home and it's
something that we talk about a lot and I
think that it's something that we really
can't emphasize enough you know in the
situation because it's all too easy to
get into a situation and feel like man I
just am insufficient but no like you
said a lot of times it's
there's a whole team designed to to
prevent you from doing what you're
trying to do yeah so back on the topic
of like um
pipe like pipeline having a pipeline of
books and stuff would you say that you
submit kind of all across the range of
severities or is it like do you focus on
criticals and highs yeah where do you
draw that line because I know a lot of
people especially full-time hackers like
they want to just have bugs going in so
that they can have money coming back on
a regular basis so it's not like once a
month I submit a crazy bug and I hope it
gets paid in a month because otherwise
I'm not getting out next month we're
looking at you Alex
yeah so um
I mean that that's much time on the same
program I know what the other day was
the threat model whether you're
interested in what should I report to up
to like just take a glance and that's
that uh I basically try to submit uh
impactful bugs and I on the less
impactful ones I just looked for
specific types of those
I basically also look uh not actively
like for exercises I use like there's a
reflector plugin it's really good uh
with some changes in it
um so you modified the bird plug-in yeah
basically nice
um
then
for example I don't look that much at
CSI like anymore I don't care about it
uh I don't do I don't know GitHub
searches yeah I don't know I've never
ever done a sub domain Takeover in my
life yeah uh I I mean like there are
lots of like better people with already
yeah tools to do everything so it's just
no I'm basically have to focus on some
specific things
uh and then yeah yeah did you do you do
chaining then like do you do you do you
ever so you know you're submitting all
sorts of types of phones but do you ever
say like okay I've got this bomb that
can be a medium but I know how to change
I know that this is a helpful Gadget to
chain it into a higher crit
um within the context of this program do
you ever save those loans and and not
report them till later
no no because uh
um Channing uh in this particular
program is very good yeah but usually
the cause of the issue is the one that's
actually impactful uh and the one that's
actually good and they recognize this
uh now I recognize that from the pattern
and stuff like that uh like first for
for instance I just once in uh I know I
think it was an SSR graph and openly
direct and this openly direct was
already reported uh they were good
enough to uh pay parts of the world but
because like all of the chain was not
there it didn't matter that much because
actually that wouldn't have opened
without that openly direct and even if
it's an openly direct this is my maybe
not that good of an example because I
expect Nishi but for example for
exercise is like you know from stocks in
this particular program what's the
severity right right right yeah so
that's that I don't like if if you have
like a specific
proof of concept to an account takeover
is fine you can use it but that's not
like a bargain itself so and change very
quickly I
okay so it's mostly just classic bones
for you you know it's not necessarily
that you're that you're like okay I've
got this sort of flow figured out where
if I can you know let's just say for
example I can set a header in the
response or something like that it
results in some sort of crazy thing it's
it's very varying volume types and and
you know not even crazy amounts of
chains uh yes and no like I know a lot
of Niche interesting stuff right I'm not
the vulnerable in itself but helps the
Recon process a lot like very small
things like uh when you ping aside to do
a post requests on HTTP https right
directed to some interesting stuff
interesting like very small things yeah
I know how to hit like a specific path
that stops at the load balancer level
doesn't go through so it's extremely
fast uh
stuff like that so if you're walking us
through your your tricks.txtricks.thxt
that's awesome yeah and I think that but
I mean we make fun of his little
tricks.txt thing but actually that that
is pivotal you know that that is
absolutely pivotal to to staying at a
Target long term I I have one target
that I've done you know not even close
to long as long term as as you know what
you've done but um you know even on that
you start to put when you start to piece
things together and you start
understanding these little quirks that
just tell you a little bit about how a
certain functionality is flowing and
that functionality is present across
their whole scope it makes all the
difference because you you can get that
little better it well it informs the gut
right right you know are you talking
about the the gut earlier and it informs
the gut and it allows you to get that
that sort of and even if it's just
subconscious it's like a spidey sense
exactly yeah your spidey sense but you
know there has to be something that
signals it right and and sometimes it
can be those those little tricks so that
that's that's really cool yeah I would
imagine that like there are certain
keywords right there's like things that
like you've noticed because you don't
only hack directly on that Target you
hack on other companies that will use
that the Technologies or you know will
integrate with it and
I can imagine that there are certain
things that you notice that are like oh
they're using that I now I know yeah and
then you just like focus in and just
dive in and you you start to fiddle with
things and try and find endpoints that
you can manipulate that you know how
they work and that kind of stuff yeah
that's that for sure I could recognize
like you said all the keywords the
patterns the the everything you know how
it's like you can imagine pretty well
how it's done in the background or in
the back end yeah
um yeah I also like build a ton of like
custom word lists oh that's interesting
yeah yeah I think it's super good like I
had some amazing results with the
specific workers that this is not big
like it's truly has like 10 000 words or
something how are you building that are
you are you scraping you know JS files
or map files or texts on the thing or or
is this word list.txt
tokenized into oh no
uh I think this is a pretty important
piece of my uh all right Secret Sauce
okay okay okay because if I tell you
once everybody can actually do it
because it's uh I actually read a
documentation like anywhere like this
technique right kind of but not you know
and that's that's the cool thing about
you know having people come on on the
Pod and being in the bugnani community
as well is that there there are things
that you you share and things that you
you know feel like you can give back to
the community but also like you have to
you have to keep some of that okay
so competitive and I talk to people
about the industry fairly often right
and they're like why would anybody ever
share anything right like and because
it's like you're literally creating uh
opponents you're you're creating people
that will that will steal bounties steal
literally steal money yeah right and uh
but I think that's part of the beauty
and that Dynamic is really interesting
because it in general I think it's a
really collaborative environment
um and and we in general we really lift
each other up but you know but it's also
another Point like another point of view
here yeah like if you have all those
it's very good like when I started there
was not that many resources at all right
but then you like you have like maybe
five to ten super good resources and
yeah we use that one and nobody actually
innovates a new stuff like what I did
was like I never ever read a blog post
on that in my life in the beginning yeah
ever so it kind of like forces you to
think a bit for yourself outside of the
box or like two sides of the coin yeah
that that's that's
super super important and really well
said I think that you you can get lost
you know we talked about this a little
bit on the what was that episode that I
just like made up a bunch of words that
were like Dr Seuss I forgot what that
was oh yes but but
the oh man what was it the the beginner
tips or something yeah yeah we'll we'll
link it in the description or whatever
we'll call it you know Justin's weird
episode with all the doctors yeah
um but yeah you know it's so easy to get
caught up in the education piece
especially with all the resources now
and we say like ah you know I wish I had
all these resources when I had just
started but it but actually maybe it's
better right you know maybe if maybe
it's better that you had to get your
hands in there and figure it out for
yourself in a lot of ways
um because then you you do figure out
how to develop methodologies and it
takes more time and it takes a little
bit of a grind for sure because I've
seen I've seen hackers go from zero to
like finding crits on hard programs in
like less than two years you know with
the resources two months yeah yeah I
mean true yeah some people just really
didn't take it quick depending on the
background but I've seen someone
literally go I'll call it out so
um my my mentee so he he went from
you know French major to finding crits
you know in in less than two years like
on him on his own you know and and uh
and you know it's definitely possible
with the resources but also you know a
big part of our our flow you know
working together to help him grow as a
hacker was doing doing a lot of hacking
yeah and then we would you know maybe we
would do five or six hours of hacking
together in a day and then he would go
home and read five hours of resources
yeah right and so he was really putting
in the time
um and those resources are great but it
has to be it has to be has to be has to
be accompanied with failing right you've
got to get out there and fail and and
you know develop your own techniques
because that's where you get the secret
sauce right like this that that cosmen
has that's that's super clutch so I
guess one of the other things that I had
on the list for you regarding a specific
you know working with one specific uh
program over the long term is your
relationship with the team game like how
has your relationship with the team
evolved and how have you
um how has that helped you as as a
hacker or as a participant in that
program so
um I've always had a very good
relationship with the whole team yeah uh
even if they change the management the
new employees all yeah and so on
um because I always felt appreciated by
them and what I said was like impactful
it was publicly analyzed I I never felt
like tweaked or something like that so
it was like I think it's also a very
mutual it's full of mutual respect and
also yeah when they needed something for
me I was there for them right when I
needed something from from them they
were there for me yeah so it's pretty
important yeah that that's really good I
I will say you know
and I imagine that takes a lot of effort
on your behalf as well because
especially with the you know report a
bug and forget it mentality like
sometimes you
you'll report a bug you know month will
pass and they'll be like hey
um clarifying detail on this then I'm
like I don't even remember where that
was you know like and you got to go back
and like figure out like all the
different details about it so that takes
work uh I I don't assume this ever
happened what yeah ever because they
have
um a specific attached team like they
yeah the entire team and they are
accustomed to the product so that's when
I have questions they do it like
beforehand and then go through some I
don't know what the back end that
process looks like I have no idea yeah
but they give all the details and um
yeah maybe like
two or three times yeah let's get
qualifications how I found something
like how I reached uh results but this
was not like a technical question wow
that that's that's actually really
that's really amazing because you know I
feel like especially as remediation
starts to come into effect a lot of
times I get another question like hey
could we fix this by this and then I'm
like uh not really sure because I don't
remember any of the details of this bug
yeah
um and and so it seems like they've got
a lot of technically competent people on
the back end that yeah don't even
necessarily need to double check with
you you know they can just kind of
look look at the code talk to their own
you know security team and figure that
out so that's cool yeah yeah and if you
can bypass it great you know like
there's another value for you yeah so
when you fi when you're when you submit
bugs to other programs that are outside
of the main thing that you hack on but
are like yeah usually usually using that
technology would you say that it's
something that you have found on the on
the main technology and then gone to
check if it's on other programs or is it
you're just curious you're looking at
that program you stumble on the
technology and you're like oh okay let's
let's exploit this uh
yes so um I've I've never consciously
like sent a report on a program that
uses a technology when I knew that that
was a cog issue
um because they truly frown upon that so
that's like a double dipping
like a huge no and if I find something
that happened like maybe two times you
find something on a program that is a
technology and I'm not sure whether
that's like a configuration thing or
it's a call issue tested on something
that I own and to see that's a core
issue so I know exactly where to submit
it's nice oh my gosh that that must take
so much effort though because you gotta
go reset up that whole project yeah so
for yourself you do a lot of testing on
like a local instance or whatever that
you have configured and set to defaults
and so yeah I have a lot of uh various
test instances nice different purposes
all called ASDF right yeah yeah one
asdf2
basically I usually it's been a new one
if like I'm out of storage or or the
name is taken it was funny because
during one of your show and tells you're
you're showing like the configuration
that you had used or whatever for like
you're just like a setup or something
and it was like city name
that's that's actually me uh like trying
you know usually is
yeah there was an address and it was it
was streets
yeah so you can you can like actually
realize it's not like a placeholder
right Street City
Arkansas
we both knew it was Arkansas
yeah I was like Cosmic Arkansas
that's hilarious man
no I forget yeah I didn't even I kind of
forgot that that was a state
oh man yeah no that's that's great
um cool man well let me see let me see
what else I've got on the list here
because we we had a great we've had a
great conversation so far
um
yeah uh so I guess
we talked a decent bit about what it
means to be on on one target for the
long term the last thing that I had was
like how do you create mental models or
or do you intentionally create mental
models for how a product works and do
you store those in your you know
notes.txt or do you kind of keep them
all up in your head just architecturally
and also like structurally so here
um I could definitely recognize I have a
problem
[Laughter]
we realize how it works yeah and maybe I
edited the text file yeah so yeah I
actually went like husbands doing like
ASCII art in his like frogs exactly how
I feel every time I come back to a
program that I haven't touched in like a
while yeah I'm like oh oh and then it
all clicks I'm like oh God I remember it
now yeah something like something like
that so um I went like
like to serve the same parts of the app
multiple times and I know that was not
efficient that good it was kind of
frustrating sometimes because you don't
find the results you know it's dead we
just like forgot that specific URL chair
but I usually remember how I got the I
remember the process
yeah and I think you you told me before
this event that you've actually seen a
decent amount of the targets that were
in scope you know before and so it's
it's pretty it's pretty clear you know
that the you can come back you mentioned
earlier I mean it was really interesting
you you said you'll you'll hit a mental
block and then you'll you'll come back
you know later afterwards and that's
really like that does not work at all
for me like for me I've got to be I've
got hit a mental block and then just
iterate again and then iterate again
while I've got it all in my brain right
and then you know really if I'm like
really really stuck in something's close
maybe I'll like force myself to move
along and but still be thinking about it
in like a background process but like I
don't move
along very easily and then come back to
something and it seems like that's
something that you do so that's an
interesting tip yeah so I do that like
you said but I also have to hit a Blog
if I'm in the zone I'm not like
switching targets or anything but if I
exhaust like the things I wanted to try
yeah uh I may move to something else
then uh maybe come back especially life
hacking events because um I picked up I
uh something like
British hello yeah so it does not and I
just like went there so I could actually
afford to ping pong a bit Ah nice yeah
so also like on the big thing that I do
I do the same thing
um because sometimes I actually missed
things uh or have like a new Fresh idea
that would work yes like later you
notice some weird Behavior yeah
exactly so I think
it's pretty important to know what's
going on
how you achieve that result uh like the
whole process but
maybe it's not as important to know all
the details if you know how to get the
details again yeah yeah and if it makes
sense yeah no that definitely makes
sense I think it's I think like you said
intuitively that's not the most
efficient flow but I think maybe even
going through that exercise of
rediscovering yeah exactly the the
functionality can firm up your
understanding because it's almost like
you're coming back with semi-fresh eyes
right you know like if I have a problem
with something I'll hit up Joel and Joel
will come look at it he's got a fresh
set of eyes he sees something different
right but you know maybe if I don't hit
up Joel and I spend a couple days you
know doing something else and then I
come back to it you know my eyes are
sort of not as as fresh with it and
maybe I'll see something different as
well that sound it seems like what
you're doing yes yes yes yes yes yes
exactly so what you're telling me is I
can cut Joel out of the bounty process
between those processes you also learn
new new things that on the second
integration you can apply them also
there and it's actually kind of built
also in my tours my tools we integrated
their own previous results from other
places and try to do that again in a new
environment ah and actually I have
results like if you have my the tool
that I have in a blank and you machine
yeah it would not have like many hits
but if you like we integrate on a big
like data it kind of like tries to do
the same stuff again and like it's
really interesting to hear hear like
other hackers describe this because I
think it's almost like you have your own
little internal like live hacking event
where your knowledge sharing with
yourself yeah
it's like it's like it's so weird
because every time we go to
and like if you're collaborating with
someone they'll be like hey I have this
really weird behavior and I find that
nine times out of ten I'll be like oh
have you tried this this and they're
like yep I tried all that stuff didn't
work and I was like oh man okay so we're
thinking about this the same way hot
cosmen like Scrolls up and notes that
takes
guess what I have this weird Behavior
maybe you can figure it out thanks
oh my gosh sharing sharing tips with
yourself
next level [__] right here you know
people are coming into this this
interview you know yeah it's Cosmic he's
gonna have some crazy [__]
just sitting at home talking to itself
I was like I've got this
this
got updated
let's go oh my gosh you guys are you
guys are too much man
um yeah all right well I mean that's
that's all I had on my list do you have
any um any I guess let me ask this um
do you have any tips or tricks I think
you're the leading expert that I can
think of on staying on one program for a
long term and making a [__] ton of money
on it like do you have any any tips for
for people that relate to long-term
relationship building with one program
and would you recommend that to all
hackers
uh yeah I think everybody has its own
way yeah that different type of people
uh that some some go wide some go deep
some focus on specific vulnerability
Times They are all very successful yeah
so in the scope of a question for me
personally it does uh very fortunate and
good to go this path and having a good
relationship with the program I think
it's crucial yeah and but that can be
seen pretty fast like after a few months
I think you can actually get an idea of
what's happening and you could decide
for yourself whether to perceive that
program just to stop because if you feel
like you're being tricked or not
appreciated
uh you cannot do it long term I think
yeah
um I I have a little interesting
perspective on this as well because I've
been on the company side I've actually
been on the company side that you've
reported stuff to as well yeah exactly
and um and
I think
certain researchers really demonstrate
like just in how they report and what
they report like the type of like person
that they are the type of Hunter they
are and the type of relationship that
they're trying to build and so like if
you're submitting critical stuff and
like you're doing your best to be like
open honest and transparent about that
yeah you're consistent right it's more
like once you get two or three reports
into a program they know your name like
right they're gonna know it especially
if those are really good well-written
reports and that's like what you do
right and so like I don't think I've
ever seen a report from you that's been
like Ugh uh this this report sucks like
yeah you read this right right because
like you you have a reputation and that
reputation holds up so I think it's
important not only for like the program
side the program side will probably pick
up on it like once you start reporting
because they see that you're interested
and they're like oh awesome this person
is is actively like hacking system you
know we want them to keep going like we
want to keep seeing bugs from this
person and that's like an awesome thing
to see as a program it's just like
somebody who's finding cool [__] that
you've missed yeah yeah I think you
mentioned in the past too that you you
have like I remember you saying like ah
this this one bug is like 20 steps long
right and and I'm like and I'm like man
I don't know that I've ever written a
report that's that's like you know 15
Steps long right so I think probably
there's a lot of detail that goes into
your reports too uh yeah so this is
actually excuse that you have to develop
for yourself to learn to write a good
reports yes extremely extremely
important yeah it cuts out of
frustration yeah faster I'm talking
about times and everything so yeah it's
really good do you do video pocs I
almost always the video series if it's
some somehow like complex if it's like
an exorcist I put the screenshot yeah
yeah that's that but if it's like
something complex uh I do a video POC
but I also realized that it's extremely
important to properly write the
application steps because nobody wants
to like open a video in a new screen and
a new screen or something and then just
like uh yeah I have to do that let me
pause the video oh what what did you do
today rewind how can I copy this I
cannot copy this we're like copying the
video into 16 different ticket programs
you've got inside of a you know jira and
this and that so yeah yeah exactly so
both parts are important and I I usually
have like a really structurally blocked
uh
um like I have a summary describes the
vulnerability a bit it's a new program I
tend to like give explanations about
like why this is happening Sometimes
some of her cases I give a documentation
like links uh site documentation back to
them yeah yeah and then like the
application steps uh I write down video
screenshot attached the impact section
already impacting is that so yeah I feel
like especially for other teams that
aren't the main program that you that
you're on like
a lot of the time they don't even fully
understand like the technology that
you're hacking on and so it's like
difficult for them to know why it's a
security impact so I think that's really
important for like you who has really
really deep understanding of like why is
this bad and how it's bad and that this
is like a default configuration or
something like that to explain to the
security team so that they can
understand it because oftentimes it's an
engineering Focus that the engineering
team has chosen to use this technology
and it's more convenient for them but
the security team isn't in on that
decision right they're just there as the
security team and then they find out
later that it's been done improperly
yeah yeah exactly exactly yeah that that
so Okay so we've got you know being
consistent you've got writing writing
really solid reports and then you said
within the first like two or three
months you'll kind of know whether the
team is like some some buddy you'd want
to work with continuously
um besides those three do you have any
other tips for people wanting to develop
along to find their you know bread and
butter program their program that
they're going to stick with long term
what other kind of tips and indicators
do you have you have to like hacking it
yeah
yeah I have some technologies that
and I
to close the program but yeah I can also
afford to do that now and just like move
to something else I didn't not even
start but surely you dislike this
program you know sometimes oh yeah yeah
so that happens do you okay so you know
would you say that there are periods of
like
you know a week or would you say that
there are periods of a couple days where
you're like oh man like I am really
sloshing through this right now like I
really don't want to be doing this like
you know how long do you think those
periods last versus like the the
eventual come around which is like ah
you know what actually this is pretty
good
uh uh it's kind of I know it's hard to
quantify but yeah so
if I have like a disagreement or
something yeah not necessarily with the
program but like with the technology
like do you ever like to get burned out
basically what oh yeah okay it's not
even burned out like do you well maybe
sort of but like do you ever think like
I really don't like hacking this
technology right now or is it pretty oh
yeah yeah yeah okay I understand what
you mean yeah uh this happens this
happens
first times yeah and I just uh try to
hack something else and that's the point
when sometimes I switch to other
programs that I had but usually I just
see if I have some interesting invites
like to start somewhere fresh uh so you
bounce bounce out for just a second and
maybe the live hacking events even help
with this uh yeah yeah for sure those
those actually help us uh if it's a life
hacking event I just focus on that so
it's like nothing else yeah it just
bounce out a little once in between and
then usually come back to see if like
something new I have another idea what
does my text files says yes
you have like an ideas.txt as well oh my
gosh that you keep like things that are
kind of interesting but maybe not fully
formed yeah that's part of notes yeah
you got it oh man that's awesome yeah so
that's great I mean that that's really
odd you know you'd think it's obvious
advice but I think for people that are
be motivated and people that really want
to succeed they just try to like you
know just make it happen right and and I
think that's one of the things and this
is applicable to life too it's not just
bug Bounty is like you ought to like the
thing you're trying to succeed in you
know for sure and if you don't maybe you
should switch because at the end of the
day
um if you don't like it at a lower level
it's going to be really hard for you to
push through long term and in just a
little bit of liking it I think goes a
long way too yeah you know yes yeah it's
exactly what we talked about with like
when like beginners try to pick their
first program yeah like I always say
like just pick like something that
you're that like you use on a daily
basis or that you like you you think
it's a cool technology or like when you
read the company name you're like I'll
be epic if I could hack the US
Department of Defense right right it's
like just pick something that like seems
interesting to you and set that goal for
yourself because that like that genuine
attraction towards the product towards
the towards the program is going to
drive you to like try and find those
epic bugs right like you want to like
find something super epic maybe it's for
bragging rights but also just for like
you know I hacked the dod or I hacked
whatever right it's like it's like yeah
right yeah it's really important yeah no
that that's right it just makes me think
of that that thing we were laughing
about the other day in one of the hacker
chats we're in of like
um someone released like a list of like
top 100 most secure companies or
something like that and we're like oh no
like why would you do this and and some
you know some hacker out there is
definitely gonna be like there's my top
10 list yeah I'm gonna pone all of these
yes no that's good that that definitely
makes sense and and I'm sure there's
lots of complex intricacies to
developing you know your your bread and
butter program you know we heard we
heard lots of documentation we heard
good reports we heard like the product
we heard you know value your
relationship with that with the company
step away when you're not feeling it
yeah bounce away when you're not feeling
it and then come back to it and and
check and see whether that that that
feeling of love you know is still there
for the programs and I love that Nuance
because it's like yeah you know you can
be like I mean you are like the most
quintessential like single program
hacker that I can think of yeah and yet
you still take breaks from the program
you just switch it up you still do
different stuff and like you're still
able to go back and like crush it
like regularly because of all those
other things that you're doing like
taking breaks and taking notes and
writing good reports and having that
relationship with the team yeah all the
sometimes it also helps like uh building
your own tools around something that you
can know
um
uh also as a break yes
um the
also you have to think about well what
can I add to that and you can research
into that uh area in particularly again
you learn a little bit more and then you
can automate it maybe just integrate it
in a flow or whatever works for you yeah
nice but but I think you can't take
these breaks if you're stressed out
about money yeah right exactly yeah it
definitely does it's definitely someone
that you know you need to be in a in a
financially secure position to be able
to commit to a program long term like
this yeah for sure and and so you know
this particular program that you work on
you know there there are a couple
hackers that that you know have this as
their main thing so do you ever see a
decent amount of overlap with other
hackers do you I mean like why would you
say your dupe ratio is in this program
like five was too much one was too late
yes
that has been like that since
it's not that important to look at the
thank you though yeah yeah the activity
or whatever the top we talk about that
all the time you know people get scared
Away by that little that little you know
top hackers in this program thing yeah
everyone has different eyes man yeah and
if I recall correctly you're not even
number one on this program no there's
somebody else who is yeah it's crazy
which is I can't even fathom yeah yeah
yeah yeah exactly
so like you said everybody is different
and yeah like has their own way and yeah
just go in if you like it yeah wow great
great tips man
um thank you so much for coming on the
pods
um yeah I I will definitely have to put
your brain again sometime maybe next
time you win a belt
awesome all right thanks man thank you
[Music]
thank you
foreign